<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Greg&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://win32.gg/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Greg&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://win32.gg/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asterisk quick startup</title>
      <link>https://win32.gg/posts/asterisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://win32.gg/posts/asterisk/</guid>
      <description>SIP and VoIP Voice over IP is a standard for for communication over IP. It is used in a lot of applications, especially in recent communication software and aims at replacing RTC, traditional telephone lines. SIP is the protocol implementing a VoIP standard compatible with telephones, SIP client software and compatible phones. Asterisk is a software with a lot of capabilities, phone-book, voice mail and SIP server.
Prerequisites VoIP implies an already working IP stack with a backbone IP network, DHCP if you want to and to open ports on the Asterisk host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openvpn Manager</title>
      <link>https://win32.gg/posts/openvpn-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://win32.gg/posts/openvpn-manager/</guid>
      <description>What to do OpenVPN is an open-source VPN software commonly used in universities, workplaces or even homelabs. I always liked using it and it actually taught me a lot regarding certificates (it used to be shipped with easy-rsa), networking, routing etc&amp;hellip; At the time I started to need to use it at scale for my lab I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any tool with a web interface. I seems everybody just loved to make their own script to add new users and well&amp;hellip; so did I.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
